Surgeons are
the biggest hypocrites.
We tell our patients to rest
as we work 100-hour weeks.
You don't wanna be late.
You're on my service today.
I think I've been servicing you
since last night.
You want me to stop?
We tell residents
to have good bedside manner...
Oh.
...then we yell at them
for the smallest mistakes.
You follow instructions well.
Well, I aim to please.
And that's why
breakfast is on me.
I'm starving.
This feels
mildly transactional.
But I'm not opposed.
Aren't you a vegetarian?
Vegan, actually. Why?
Oh, you just ordered,
uh, carnitas.
That was for a coworker.
At 2:00 a.m.?
You're not the only one
who eats breakfast.
We tell our kids
to chase their dreams
as we constantly question
our life choices.
Hi. The answer is still no.
I consult on your patients.
When was the last time
I referred you a patient?
-What is a substitute
for vanilla?
-Are you doing a crossword?
I'm baking.
Okay, you need to go
back to work.
Patient's name is Emma.
She's five months pregnant
with severe headaches.
-Yeah, I read your emails.
-So, what do you think?
Well, it could be anything.
It could be migraines, CVST.
It's hard to say
without imaging.
Uh... Do you think
I could use honey?
One second,
there's someone at the door.
What?
So, will you do her scans?
I am on sabbatical.
Why are you here?
Because you cannot say no
to this face.
Oh.
-No.
-Come on.
Emma's waiting for us
at Grey Sloan. Go. Get dressed.
God.
We love fixing
everyone's problems.
But don't ask us
to solve our own.
-Big night?
-And morning.
It was a very hot shower.
- Well, our house
is nailing it right now.
- Gross.
Who knew Kwan with a girlfriend
would be more annoying
than Kwan without one?
-She's not my girlfriend.
-Oh, Mohanty finally dump you?
No, but we are
just not exclusive.
-You're both seeing
other people?
-He's not.
You told me you weren't.
He thinks Mohanty might be.
Okay, you are not allowed
to ride in the car
with me anymore.
Yeah, well, I'm exclusively
seeing patients.
You on cardio today?
Cardio wants nothing
to do with me, which is fine.
I'd invite you
to Hunt's ambulance ride-along,
but it is a party of one.
Which is also what it's like
for you when Mohanty's
seeing other people.
Oh.
Hilarious.
Hey. Did you already tell her?
Uh, no, we waited for you.
We don't get to do this
nearly enough. Come on.
Okay.
Stop questioning it and take the job in Paris.
We'll talk Tuesday. Bye-bye.
Oh, my gosh, my client
is great, but very stubborn.
Yeah, I think I know the type.
Katie,
this is Dr. Warren.
He and Dr. Adams
will be taking care of you
while I'm out today.
But before I go,
we have some news.
So, we got your scans.
Your primary tumor
reduced by 30%.
Mmm.
The treatment is working?
It appears that way.
Your CEA and CA 19-9 have
decreased dramatically as well.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry...
...I don't know what to say.
I mean, I know that you said
that you would find a way,
but I didn't know that
you actually could.
- Never doubt her abilities.
- Mmm.
-And you're the husband,
aren't you?
-I am.
- Oh.
- Wh-What did she say about me?
She is a professional
couples therapist.
She gives good advice.
Yeah, but-but as a pro,
you know, just...
Mmm.
So, I need to head out...
...but you are
in good hands.
I am glad
you're feeling better.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Seriously,
what did she say about me?
Hey.
I've got good news
and bad news.
Which would you like first?
- Bad.
- Good.
Patient wins.
So, the bad news is no more
hospital breakfast for you.
Because I'm being discharged?
Yes.
Your EF is normalized,
- and your dyspnea
has resolved...
...so you'll continue PT
and surveillance echoes,
but you're ready.
Oh. I get to sleep
in a normal bed
and eat normal food.
Thank you.
For everything. Okay.
- Oh, yeah.
Happy to help. Nurse will be
in soon, all right?
-Okay.
-Come here.
'Kay.
Mmm.
Are you sure you're okay
with me seeing patients today?
Yeah, you've been w-waiting
to get back into the OR
for months,
and I'm gonna spend
the day with the girls
in the NICU anyway.
I get to come home.
You get to come home.
Good morning. Are you okay?
You have a headache
or something?
It's preventative.
I get motion sickness.
Oh, would it help
if you sat up front?
Uh-uh.
Nope, I want to experience
the ride-along
like one of my residents,
so I can accurately assess
its merits.
Oh, I thought you were
optimistic about
the ride-along program
when I suggested it.
I kind of thought
this was just a formality.
Yeah, well, money's tight,
and everybody has ideas
for innovative rotations.
Is there something I can do
to move the needle,
send you some studies
of other hospital programs?
No, let's just see
what the day brings.
Okay.
Welcome to Grey Sloan.
Thanks for having us.
We were just meeting Dr. Kwan.
I don't have
any first responder experience,
so this will be great.
Well, meet Jackie and Greg.
They will be showing us
how to triage and stabilize
in the field
and how they transfer patients
to the hospital.
For everyone's safety,
please wait for
our instructions
and then follow them closely.
After you.
Oh.
Watch your step.
There'll be no telling
what the day will bring.
Except waiting.
There's always waiting.
Which brings us
to your first lesson,
arguably the most important.
Who knows how to play Speed?
Off to a great start.
Mrs. Tucker in bed five
has been discharged,
and I hear there's another
empty bed in the on-call room.
-How can you think about
that right now?
-I think about it a lot.
You just changed a wound vac
on a 92-year-old man.
Yeah, and it reminded me
that life is short.
Okay, but we have
to keep it professional here.
We're dealing with
people's lives. It's serious.
- Hey.
-  -Hey, oh, what happened?
I slipped on baby oil.
I think I busted my hip.
Okay, let's get you to a bed.
This way.
Yes, work is
very, very serious.
You good?
Yeah, I thought
I'd feel weirder
after being gone for so long,
but feels like I was just here.
Yeah, that never goes away.
Uh, Dr. Montgomery.
Dr. Shepherd,
I didn't know you were back.
I'm not back.
Well, I'm on scut
all day today, so if either
of you needs a resident--
It's just a consult, Millin.
Emma, this is Dr. Shepherd, who
I've been wanting you to see.
Emma and I met on the road.
She's from Clark County, Idaho.
Dr. M's my birth control
hookup, or was.
I finally gave in
to my husband.
He's wanted a baby for years.
Well, it's very nice
to meet you.
Tell me about your headaches.
Uh, they've been
constant for two months.
My husband has had to take care
of all of our animals.
-Animals?
-Mm-hmm. We run
an animal sanctuary.
Cows, horses, goats, alpacas.
I always thought
fur babies were enough,
but now that I'm pregnant
with a human baby,
- I'm pretty attached to her too...
-  -Mm-hmm.
...and all the cute onesies
I can't stop buying.
Any numbness,
tingling, or weakness?
Squeeze my fingers.
Uh, no,
but the pain's gotten worse.
Okay. Tell me
when you see my fingers.
I've seen my OB
and been to the ER.
Everyone says it's hormones.
I see them now. Is that good?
Millin, I need a stat MRI head
without contrast
and a wheelchair.
What's happening?
-You've lost
your peripheral vision.
-W-What does that mean?
It means we need imaging
to see what's going on.
Okay.
- Speed.
- Yeah, you're kidding!
So, Jackie,
on an average day,
how many calls
for EMT services do you get?
There isn't a typical day.
Some days you're on the go,
and others you're clobbering
your partner at cards.
Oh, I'm winning this round.
But you do agree
that ride-alongs help
educate hospital staff
on first responders' roles,
and the more they know,
the better the communication,
and that improves patient care.
Sure,
if they're paying attention.
Go.
I'm married to
a former first responder.
I know there's
a lot of hurry up and wait.
Yeah.
Dispatch to Ambulance 22.
Injuries after a fall
on the football field
at Seattle West
Community College,
425 Castle Rock Road.
-Right. Here we go.
-Finally.
What do we got?
Uh. This is Jeff, 28,
pain in his right hip,
can't bear weight.
Looks like a posterior hip
dislocation due to
the place of--
Man versus baby oil.
I fell off a pole.
Jeff is a male erotic
movement professional.
Oh, no, s-stripper's fine.
Okay. Mind if I take a look?
All right.
So where do you strip?
Hot Temptations.
I started last month
working the early bird special.
Money's not great,
but it's good practice.
Hopefully soon...
...I'll get to be dancing
nights and weekends.
That's where you make it rain.
Well, we'll get you back
on that stage in no time.
Dr. Griffith and Dr. Bryant
will make you comfortable,
and we'll get that hip
back in place.
Oh. Should I page Dr. Young?
No need. Altman cleared me
for surgery yesterday.
Oh, that's
an impressive dislocation
for your first one back.
I can't believe
he got that pole dancing.
This will mean nothing to you,
but that hip looks like
Bo Jackson in the '91 playoffs.
From the Bengals game?
Yeah, he was never
the same after that.
-Could've been a league legend.
-Yeah, well, he is in my house.
My dad, ultimate Raiders fan.
Get Jeff sedated
for the reduction. And we'll
page you when he's ready.
-Okay.
Why did you do that?
We were having a moment.
In the words of John Wooden,
"Nothing will work
unless you do."
What's Little Natalia's?
Oh, it's the restaurant
for Seattle's top-ranked
New York cheesecake.
I made a reservation
for next month.
Am I being too hopeful?
Should I not celebrate?
I think you got scammed
by advertising.
I know the restaurant
with the best cheesecake.
Oh, when's the last time
you went to a restaurant?
Yeah, right,
you don't get to vote.
Well, I'm just saying
if you're gonna celebrate,
you should go bigger.
Get the best New York
cheesecake in New York.
-Yeah? Well, let me go pack.
-All right.
The original Junior's
in Brooklyn.
You know, for a doctor,
you have pretty bad judgment.
I can't go to New York.
Why not?
Because I have my treatment.
Oh, it's just one weekend.
You'll be back in this room
in no time.
Look, uh, what would you
tell your clients if they were
sitting in that chair?
I can't believe
I'm actually considering this.
Um...
But shouldn't we ask
Dr. Bailey first?
Ask after you book the flight,
then she can't say no.
Okay. Okay.
We got a call about
a football injury.
Cheerleading actually.
We usually practice in the gym
with padded mats,
but we gotta get out
in the field sometime.
That makes sense.
Okay. What happened?
-We were practicing
backflip rewinds and--
-And butterfingers dropped me.
You kicked your leg
on the toss,
fricking knocked me out.
You were out for two seconds.
You've been a suck-ass spotter
all season.
-Should I do
a primary survey on her?
-I'm a fly on the wall.
Wait for Jackie's instructions.
-She's not doing anything.
-Kwan, get over here
and help me triage.
When you arrive, you first
assess for scene safety.
All right,
let me have a look.
-What's your name?
-Rosie.
The drugs
should take effect soon.
So how did you
get into stripping?
It was my college major.
I'm kidding.
I was bagging groceries,
and I started stripping
on the side to pay for
my student loans.
Turns out it was everything
I ever wanted in a job.
Flexible hours,
I was on my feet, and I get
to make a lot of people happy.
Aside from the flexible hours,
it doesn't sound all
that different from surgery.
How do you do surgery?
-How we doing over here?
-Good.
Hey, when do the drugs
start to kick in?
He's ready.
Okay, Jeff, I'm gonna pull
your hip back into its socket.
You shouldn't feel any pain,
just some pressure.
- Bryant, will you secure his hips?
-  -Yep.
Hey, you've got a deep squat.
You could be a stripper.
Thank you, I will consider it.
All right.
There's so much baby oil.
I can't get a grip.
He's like an eel.
-Griffith, some towels, please.
-Okay.
Okay.
- All right.
- You ready, Jeff?
-One, two, three.
-Yep.
You said there'd be no pain.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I think it's
pinching your sciatic nerve.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
Let's, uh... Let's get a CT
so we can find out
what's wrong.
- I'll go grab it.
- Thank you.
It's like a coffin in here.
Wait, where are the headphones?
S-She doesn't have headphones?
-The music will distract her.
-Well, the scan's almost over.
- I'll go and get her
some headphones.
You're doing great, Emma.
You know, close your eyes.
It helps.
Did not expect
either of you in here.
-This Montgomery's doing?
-I may have called in a favor.
Just for today.
Okay, well, nice work.
I hope it sticks.
It's good to see you both.
Um...
The scans...
scans are already up.
Is that
a pituitary adenoma?
She must've had this tumor
for a while
and then she got pregnant
and the hormones made
the tumor grow.
Dr. Montgomery.
I opened my eyes.
Uh, that's okay. We're gonna
get you out of the coffin soon.
That's not the problem.
I can't see anything.
My vision...
...I think it's all gone.
Okay, the tumor just ruptured.
Let's get her out of there.
-I will page Roberts.
-Roberts?
You're gonna make me spend
four hours in an OR
with that old blowhard?
Well, I agreed to consult,
not to operate.
Well, that was before I knew
Emma needed surgery.
-I am on sabbatical.
-Jake...
Jake's leaving me.
I don't wanna talk about it.
I don't want you to ask
any questions about it.
All I want is for Emma
to get the best care possible,
and that's you.
I will get
my privileges reinstated.
Oh. Can you see
what's blocking the reduction?
That bone fragment.
Posterior wall
acetabular fracture.
Any nerve or vascular damage?
Not yet, but the longer
we wait, the higher his risk.
Book an OR.
- Okay.
-I checked the OR board on my way here.
There's a wait list, but I'm
tight with the front desk,
so we'll get him in today.
Do what you gotta do.
All right.
What?
Just surprised you could see
the board with your head
so far up Lincoln's--
Like you never tried to
get in good with attendings
while you were an intern?
I didn't have to.
My skills spoke for themselves.
What kind of skills
are we talking about?
Is your brain
just alternating between
sex and surgery all day?
I think it's a healthy balance.
-Go sweet-talk the front desk.
-Okay.
I don't have
five to ten business days.
I need the glider today.
He just hung up on me.
What's going on?
Okay, Dr. Kasliwal
just told me that the girls
are doing really well.
They haven't needed
the bili lights
or supplemental oxygen.
Peyton's ASD is closing.
And that's a problem because?
They're being discharged today.
Our whole family's
officially out of the hospital.
Yes, but we haven't finished
the nursery. I haven't hired
a night nurse, and--
I'm-I'm scheduled to be done
painting this weekend.
I thought we liked Samantha.
Well, she kept referencing
true crime documentaries.
We like
Didn't seem like she was
sympathizing with the victims.
I see your point. Um...
I have to get to surgery,
but hey, it is gonna be okay.
I promise.
Is it?
Millin,
before you scrub,
would you go in
and help them set up the scope?
- Absolutely.
- Mm-hmm.
What happened with Jake?
Emma's in her second trimester,
so her physiology is
different than most patients.
Yeah, I'm not a resident.
What about Henry? Is he okay?
And anesthesia
can be challenging.
We need to make sure both
the mother and baby are safe.
All right,
you used your personal life
to manipulate me
into doing a surgery.
You gonna tell me
what the hell is going on?
Jake's done
supporting my work on the PRT
and wants me to come home.
Happy?
Addison.
Emma's waiting.
Kwan, say your findings
out loud like you would
in a trauma room.
Okay, neck is nontender.
Ow. My rib's gotta be broken.
Should I be headed to
a hospital?
Let us finish triaging, okay?
I feel okay. Help Rosie.
We took her vitals.
She's stable. We need
to finish your neuro exam.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
My side, I can't breathe.
If she's talking,
she's breathing.
If she dies, she will haunt me
from the grave.
I heard that.
Rosie, another team's here.
They'll take you
to the hospital.
-Kwan, grab that backboard.
-Okay.
-Whoa.
-He's seizing.
Okay, let's get him
on his side.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
You're okay.
You're all right.
Hey, so if
one of Bailey's patients
wanted to take a trip
during
her immunotherapy regimen...
I may have convinced Katie
to book a flight to New York.
How much crap will I be in?
Come look at this email.
"We write to inform you
that we have made the decision
to discontinue
the IM90 protocol."
Wait, wait, wait,
this is Katie's trial.
She's literally getting
an infusion right now.
It might be the last one.
Okay, well,
what are we gonna do?
Nothing
until we talk to Dr. Bailey.
Give him
five mgs of midazolam.
Does anyone know if he has
a history of seizures?
I've never heard anything,
and I've known him
since kindergarten.
-Is he okay?
-Uh, we're figuring it out.
Okay, yes, bring the board.
-Kwan, you call it.
-Yeah, okay. Here we go.
One, two, three.
Left pupil's blown.
Looks like a brain bleed. Kwan?
In the hospital,
I would page a neurosurgeon.
-In the field?
-We could drill a burr hole
to relieve the pressure.
I saw an IO gun
in the ambulance.
We're not drilling into
his brain if we can
get him to a hospital.
We'll send him
with them and follow up
when we get back to Grey Sloan.
Not to make this
about me, but...
We'll take you ourselves.
One, two, three.
Okay. Keep it steady.
H-Hey, you paged?
Yeah, Midtown or West Village?
Oh, uh, you're
already looking at hotels.
I got my flight.
Wait, did Dr. Bailey find out?
No. Uh. No, no, I just...
Wow, you, uh...
you move quickly.
I haven't let myself
look forward to anything
in so long.
I forgot how good it feels.
I even emailed my boss
to discuss seeing clients
in person again.
Hey, look, y-you should
probably not rush--
Relax. I'm not gonna start
tomorrow.
Don't be sad.
I'll come and visit
when I'm feeling better.
They need me for a consult.
- Wait.
Midtown or West Village?
Uh... The Village.
Approaching the skull base.
I bet Emma's husband's feeling
real guilty right about now.
- What'd he do?
- She didn't want a baby.
This was all him.
My dad didn't want kids.
That didn't work out so great for him.
Yeah, well,
Emma's on an operating table
with a camera and a curette
up her nose,
so I don't think it worked out
very great for her either.
Um...
Your mom changed
your dad's mind?
Oh, no,
she secretly stopped
taking her birth control
and then hid the pregnancy
until she was too far along
to terminate.
And my dad got over it
after he smoked
a couple of joints.
Then they went on to have
my brother, and they
do regret that one.
Hmm.
Emma said
she's happy about the baby now.
What else is she gonna say?
She's five months pregnant.
Seemed genuine.
All right,
I'm removing the bone.
I'm in the sella now.
Keep the camera close.
Successful marriages thrive on
compromises, not demands.
- She's hypotensive.
- Push fluids.
More traction, please.
- On it.
- Got it.
You know,
I never really thought
of stripping as a sport,
but I guess
it ticks all the boxes.
It's definitely athletic
and, apparently, dangerous?
Either of you play any sports?
Oh, yeah,
basketball, football, baseball,
a little bit of tennis.
I was
a competitive figure skater.
Seriously?
Like, with the jumps and stuff?
Were you any good?
My last competition,
I won silver in the free skate.
Yeah, skating is intense.
Some of the worst
injuries I've ever seen.
It's not gonna budge.
Let's, uh... Let's stop,
and we'll put in a distractor
and we'll try again.
O2's a little low.
Take a couple of deep breaths.
I hope Tim's okay.
I know he's a decent spotter.
I was just scared of Cammy.
Is that some kind of a stunt?
Cammy Lim. She's been
on the squad for two months.
She's my backup and throws
roundoff double backs
like they're nothing.
Well, there's got to be
more to being on the squad
than that roundoff thing.
Roundoff double back.
Do you know how hard that is?
Now I'm out, and they're gonna
realize she's ten times better.
Oh, I-I get it. Yeah.
You're worried
that they'll want her instead.
But you're there for a reason,
and when you come out of this,
you'll remind everyone
why that spot is yours.
- You're right. I'm a flyer.
- Hmm.
Yeah, I'm in the ambulance.
What's up?
Canceled?
Wha... Did it say why?
-I... I can't breathe.
-Okay, she's desatting.
Uh. I gotta call you back.
Okay, yeah. Decreased
breath sounds on the left.
She needs
a needle decompression.
-Yeah.
-Wait, here? In a moving rig?
We do it all the time.
-Me?
-It's your ride-along.
- Whoa!
- Sorry about that.
No more turns for a while.
Let's make this quick.
-Okay, her sats
aren't improving.
-Let me try.
Okay.
The needle decompression
is not working.
She's still retaining air
in there.
- Yeah.
- Should I put in a chest tube?
Do that at the hospital.
W-We're at least
ten minutes out.
This is field medicine.
The priority is to buy her time
and get her to Grey Sloan.
-No.
-What do you mean, "no"?
No. The longer we wait,
the more oxygen she loses,
the greater the chance of her
developing a-a tension pneumo
and rapidly decompensating.
No, I-I don't wanna take that
chance with this young woman,
not today.
Uh, give me a scalpel.
Bailey, what are you doing?
I will do
a finger thoracostomy.
Awesome.
That is not a priority. This is
a rig, not a trauma room.
-Kwan, stop.
-Kwan, give me
the damn scalpel.
She's the residency director.
BP's still soft.
Hang another bag of IV fluids.
Fluids aren't doing anything.
It's gotta be the anesthesia.
We need to counteract
the vasodilation.
- Push in pressors.
- Something is not adding up.
Are you seeing anything
on your end?
Baby's decels
are getting worse.
- We need to act now.
- I am thinking.
Well,
we don't have time for that.
- Push more pressors.
- Wait.
I understand that she's your
patient and you are worried,
-but I am the one
who is in her brain.
-Then do something!
Could it be
from the bleeding?
She has not lost
enough blood to cause this big
of a hemodynamic change.
But the hematoma was pressing
against her pituitary.
It's disrupting
the ACTH pathway.
She's in acute adrenal crisis.
Push 100 mg
of IV hydrocortisone.
Blood pressure's
coming back up.
Baby's
heart rate's improving too.
Page someone from OB
to watch the fetal monitor.
Dr. Montgomery needs a minute.
Wha... Are you... Are you
kicking me out of the OR?
What if the baby
needs to be delivered?
OB will handle it.
Let's finish
what we started. Suction.
Now that
the fragment's out,
it should reduce easily, right?
Wait, what was that?
Did it move?
Well, it should.
But we're getting nowhere.
So, the Schanz pin
gives you more control of
the femoral head, right?
Yeah.
I've never
seen that before. Could I try?
Sure.
Yeah, let's trade.
Okay,
make sure the knee's at
a 90-degree angle.
Yep.
Finally.
As long as I'm here,
would it be cool
if I put the plate on too?
Great idea.
It's a good teaching case.
- I'll guide you through it.
-  -Can I have a K-wire, please?
Yep.
Okay.
Right down there.
Looking good. Yeah.
Addison?
-Hey.
-W-Where are you?
Grey Sloan.
I've got a patient with Amelia.
How was your surgery?
I'm sorry I'm late in calling.
I-I know
you're busy. I'm doing fine.
That's good. Good to hear.
Addie, what-what's going on?
Nothing. I'm just calling
to check on you.
You're in the supply closet
on the sixth floor.
I know my hospital.
I don't know.
I am somehow turning everyone
who once supported me
into an enemy.
Amelia...
...kicked me out of the OR.
Kicked you out? Wh-Why?
I may have raised
my voice in a surgery
that I pressured her to do.
I mean,
it's not as bad as it sounds.
Did you apologize?
No, there's nothing
to apologize for.
Look, in AA,
we say the first step
is often the hardest.
It's when we admit
how powerless we are. The same
applies to relationships.
The first step is letting go of
your pride and then reaching
out to the other person.
And then the rest
will fall into place.
You always know what to say.
Sometimes I start talking
and see what comes out.
Thank you, Richard.
You take care of yourself now.
You too.
All right, what do we got?
Rosie Lang, 19 years old,
GCS 15 after a six-foot fall.
Heart rate is in the high 90s.
Status:
post needle decompression
and finger thoracostomy.
You?
Okay, BP's stable, but she
needs a chest tube right now.
Okay, let's get her
to Trauma 1.
Bailey... ...
her sats were low, but she was stable enough to make it here.
-She needed a decompression.
-Not in the ambulance.
Well, you don't know
how long she had.
If her condition worsened,
we were right there to fix it.
I'm trying to give
these residents
a better understanding
of the constraints
around prehospital medicine.
You completely
contradicted that.
Well,
I'm not gonna do nothing
if I can save a patient,
and if this ride-along
teaches otherwise,
then I don't want it
anywhere near my residents.
The dislocation was worse
than we initially expected,
but we were able to repair
your hip.
Thank you so much.
You're gonna have to
stay off of it for a while,
but with regular use and PT,
you should regain
full function.
Regular should be easy
at Hot Temptations.
No, maybe it's a sign
I'm not meant to strip.
No.
Hey, don't let one setback
derail your dream, okay?
You heal, recover
and practice your ass off.
Because...
...you belong on that stage.
That pole?
That is yours for the taking.
You grab it.
Hold tight.
Make it rain.
You're right, this was a sign.
But the sign doesn't say,
"Stop grinding."
It says...
"Grind a little slower."
Mm-mmm.
Maybe you shouldn't,
'cause you...
- Yeah. All right.
- Yeah.
Hey!
You dug deep for that one, huh?
I've given a lot of pep talks
to sad athletes,
but that was
my first stripper speech.
You did great.
Well, so did you.
You really stepped up.
Thank you.
Why'd you have to shark
my spot? You know I was
trying to get in with Lincoln.
Your spot?
Yeah, I pulled the strings
to get us an OR,
and if not for me, you wouldn't
have been there at all.
You think you're the only one
who has a hookup
at the front desk?
I still put in the work, so--
It doesn't matter.
I'm your boss.
Everything is mine until
I give it to you, and it's not
just because I can.
I know things you don't.
There were dynamics in that OR
-you were oblivious to.
-Like--
'Cause you were trying
to impress an attending.
And if you can't handle that,
I don't think we should be
hooking up anymore.
Si...
All right, tell me you got
someone on the damn phone.
We called
ten other trial sites.
They all got the same email,
same explanation.
Yeah, the trial
no longer aligns with
the center's priorities.
Which means the government
revoked the damn funding.
Yeah.
Sorry, Miranda.
- Does she know?
- No.
He... I mean, yeah,
that is growth, okay?
I am...
I am proud of both of you.
So, I will see you next week.
Yes, in person.
Okay. Bye-bye.
You're working again.
Yeah, well, it turns out
I actually enjoy what I do,
and now that
my tumors are shrinking,
I can do it a little longer.
Maybe even travel?
Please tell me
that face is not about me.
that you had a bad day
with another patient.
So...
...your clinical trial
lost its funding
and has been canceled.
But I just had an infusion.
Yes, and as of now,
that is the last one.
Look, I am at a loss too.
I am, uh, so sorry.
But look, no, no, right now
your trajectory is positive,
and I promise you
that I will do everything in
my power to keep it that way.
Okay, so...
So, i-if-if I stop taking
the medicine...
uh...
does that mean
that the tumors will come back?
I don't know.
Wha...
I am sorry. I am so sorry.
Okay...
Okay.
No... Okay, okay, okay.
Come, come, come. Oh.
Oh, boy. I'm sorry.
Oh, oh. I'm sorry.
Okay, okay.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
The look on his face
after was priceless.
Oh, uh, I'll catch you later.
Hey.
Wanna get food and then
head back to your place?
-Who was that?
-Colin. Nurse in plastics.
We built a nose
from a rib today.
Is, uh, Colin
a burrito guy, or...
I don't know.
Haven't asked. Why?
I'm not seeing other people.
I'm not seeing
anyone else either.
So what about the carnitas?
Carnitas have been over
for a few weeks.
Oh. Okay.
So maybe you and I just...
Keep it a two-person meal?
Are we really
gonna keep speaking in food?
Food is my love language.
Millin told me you were here.
She said Emma seems hemostatic,
no CSF leak.
Yeah. No, she's gonna be fine.
You know, Jake
used to be in it with me.
He used to call me
every morning
when I was on the road
and give me these pep talks.
Tell me how brave I was...
for doing work
no one else would do.
Mm-hmm.
He'd send me
these care packages
with birth control pills.
Yeah, and talk through
difficult cases with me.
He was on my side.
But now he hardly calls,
and when he does, he complains
about traffic on the 405.
You know,
or Henry's school or...
me.
'Cause he wants you home?
He says when I'm home,
I'm barely there,
you know, and he's...
He's right.
I'm not a good partner.
I forgot an anniversary.
Forgot a birthday.
I am not the woman
he married anymore.
But nothing is
what it used to be.
-I don't even
recognize science anymore.
-Mmm. No. Nobody does.
All I know is
that I can't stomach
sitting on the sidelines
and watching people die,
so I'm gonna choose work,
and if that blows apart
my life, then...
I think
if he's asking you to choose,
something's probably
already fundamentally broken.
I am...
sorry if I rushed you
back into an OR.
No... No, I-I'm not.
And we saved Emma.
And I was able to do that
because of my time away.
If I had just kept
powering through, I don't know
where I would be right now.
God.
I am a dumpster fire.
For once it's not me.
Hmm.
You look like you just worked
a double shift at Jimmy's
and you have to study
for an O-chem final.
If only.
-Are you still freaking out?
-A little.
But I got a few names
of some nurse's aides
who are looking for part-time
nanny work, so it's a start.
Baby steps.
-Pun intended.
-Yeah.
Really leaning into
those dad jokes.
-I got four kids now.
-I know.
-How'd your surgery go?
-Uh, the patient's doing well.
Um...
I know we were gonna stagger
our family leave,
but what if I just took it now?
Really?
We've both been through
so much, and like you said,
we've got more kids
than we know what to do with.
Did you hear that, girls?
Daddy's coming home with us.
Daddy's coming home.
If you're looking for an update
on Rosie, she's stable.
Yeah, I-I saw that, thank you.
- And so is Tim.
- Hmm.
I have a patient
with advanced gastric cancer
who's in a clinical trial
that was canceled today.
-Was the trial working?
-It was.
It gets worse.
I treated this patient's
grandmother for gastric cancer
when I was a resident.
She didn't make it.
Katie's poor mother
might lose a parent and a child
to the same disease,
same doctor.
It's genetics, Bailey.
It's not you.
I know.
I was overzealous today
with Rosie.
I think I needed to feel like
I could save her
right then and there,
but that's a me problem.
And I-I approved your program
for a six-month trial period.
-Wait, you did?
-Yeah.
It fulfilled all of my criteria
and then some.
Most of all,
it'll teach our residents
to handle circumstances
beyond their control.
Thank you, Bailey.
I mean, you gotta admit
that finger thoracostomy
was a thing of beauty.
I cannot argue with you there.
Sometimes hypocrisy
catches up to us.
That's when things
get interesting.
Mmm.
Okay.
-Mmm.
-What do you think?
Hmm.
Fine, I'll go back to work.
I want to like them.
But they're really...
really bad.
Will you stay the course?
- I didn't have vanilla.
Keep on keeping on,
business as usual?
May I come in?
-Talk fast.
-Yeah.
Uh, I wanna apologize.
You know, you were right.
I need to respect you
and respect that when we're
at work, you're my boss.
-Thank you.
-Yeah, no prob.
There's one more thing.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
I find powerful women
very, very, very sexy.
Now watch this shoulder.
Ah, ho ho ho.
Left shoulder.
Whoo.
Body roll.
I mean...
Or take your own advice
and change for the better.